

CONTACTS



arkahome@gmail.com



+91 8961497680



Hyderabad, India



arkapravabandyopadhyay

SKILLS

Statistics Data **Pre-processing** Modelling **Data Visualization** (Tableau) **Data Engineering** (Hadoop, Spark, Scala) SQL (Oracle 11g, Mysql) Cloud (AWS) NLP **Deep Learning**

SOFTWARE TOOLS

Python (Numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, keras, pytorch,flask)



R Programming



Data Visualization with Tableau



ARKA PRAVA BANDYOPADHYAY

Sr. Data Scientist, Legato - An Elevance Health Company, Hyderabad

5.5+ years of experience with demonstrated expertise in Machine Learning, Deep Leaning, Data Mining, Analytics & with strong business acumen. I prefer to work in the intersection of business and technology to derive real business value from data assets. Generally my experience has been to collaborate with the stakeholders to develop strategy and approach to define business challenges answered by data science to turn data into information/ to automate tasks requiring cognitive abilities with the help of AI.

AWARDS

Winner Of Capgemini I&D Organized Global Data Science Challenge (2nd) April 2018

In this competition I made a Reference Recommender System for Capgemini's sales team based on TF-IDF and Cosine Similarity and other extracted features.

EXPERIENCE

SR. DATA SCIENTIST

LEGATO – HYDERABAD

Apr 2021 - Present

Working on identifying fraud waste and abuse in healthcare payment integrity system. **Projects:**

- Worked on multiple industry standard edits and vendor insourcing projects which are on its path to production and will result in multi-million-dollar savings. The projects include revenue code that requires hcpcs code, MUE outpatients, NCCI PTP Edits Outpatients, Covid Drive Through Testing, Inappropriate modifier, base code quantity, MUE professional, NCCI Bundling professional, single line anaesthesia.
- Led the initiative to improve the model deployment process, collaborated with PE, DE and DS team to create the framework to implement model validation.
- Conceptualized and built Timber Revolution, an end-to-end PI model value generation workflow/webapp.
- Worked with the FReD team to reduce the api creation time from 14 days to 2 hours. **DATA SCIENTIST** Nov 2018 - Apr 2021

RR DONNELLEY – CHENNAL

Worked on projects based on NLP, Machine Learning and Analytics.

- AI Driven pro-forma rollover process automation using NLP Implemented Machine Learning based sentence classifier model which automatically makes the changes in the given 10K/10Q document based on the semantic understanding of the sentences which significantly reduced our AHT by around 95%.

- End to end analytics solution to maximize customer satisfaction and job volume growth.

DATA SCIENTIST

Dec. 2016 - Nov 2018

CAPGEMINI - CHENNAL

Worked with an Indian Automotive Major to derive most value from their telematics data (sensor data) at client location.

Projects:

Helped the Indian automotive major to identify key trends (market shift by seasonality using the shift of vehicle hotspots, Fuel pilferage, service centre positioning, battery failure prediction, rogue dealer identification)

EDUCATION

B.Tech In Computer Science

RCC Institute Of Information Technology (BOARD:WBUT)

Higher Secondary Examination

AMAR KRISHNA PATHSALA (BOARD:WBCHSE)

Secondary Examination

AMAR KRISHNA PATHSALA (BOARD:WBBSE)

2012 - 2016

8.29 CGPA

2010 - 2012

2009-2010

85.5%

84%